Guide to the Marcus Cunliffe papers, 1960-1990 MS0125.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Research notes and articles, 1823-1988; MS0125 Series 6; 14 Linear feet (Box 46, Box 45, Box 66, Box 65, Box 64, Box 63, Box 69, Box 68, Box 67, Box 58, Box 70, Box 71, Box 72, Box 62, Box 61, Box 60, Box 59, Box 57, Box 55, Box 56, Box 74, Box 73, Box 75, Box 49, Box 50, Box 47, Box 48, Box 53, B
  - Articles on the Janet Cooke-Pulitzer Prize controversy, 04/1981 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Articles on women's rights, 1853-1874 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Aspects of religion, 1800-1860 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Audio cassette - "Walt Whitman: Poetry and politics" (Woodrow Wilson Center), undated (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - BBC program on "The Americans" -- correspondence and notes, 1975-1977 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Behavioral sciences, 1957 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Bibliographies on American Thought and Society, 1964 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Brazilian perspective of American Literature, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - British army as an institution [1813-1870] - notes, 1946 ca. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's draft of "The British Army as an Institution, 1815-1854" (271 typescript pages), 1955 ca. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - British views of Britain, 1823-1960 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Canada and the U.S., 1952-1961 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Capitalism: Monopolies and Trusts, 1972-1984 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Carter, Ford, Reagan and the Election of 1976 and clipping on Monarchy and Republic, 1976-1982 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Charles Edward Lester, 1954 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Chattel and wage slavery: conclusions (C.E. Lester), 1837-1977 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Chicago slums - articles, 1962-1964 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Civil War historiography, 1961 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Clippings on Aphrodite head found in British Museum, undated (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Columbia University Press Manual for the Study of Contemporary Civilization - Section X (Economic Liberalism), 1941 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Columbia University Press Manual for the Study of Contemporary Civilization - Section XI (French Revolution), 1941 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University Press Manual for the Study of Contemporary Civilization - Section XII (Romanticism and Reaction, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Comic books - "Heroes of Sports" (1984) and "Hydrogen Bomb" (1970), undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Comic history of the U.S., undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Comparative aspects of American history, 1883-1982 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Comparative studies - notes, 1970-1972 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Conditions in contemporary England, 1974-1975 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Constitutional problems - non U.S. and general, 1976-1981 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Contemporary American Literature - bibliography, undated (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Counterfactual history, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Cultural patrimony - notes, c.1982, undated (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Cunliffe's work with German Festschrift on Thomas Jefferson, 1958-1972 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Democracy and the Demotic -- majority opinion and literary culture, 1957-1984 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Democratie en Amerique - French map showing the U.S. during de Tocqueville's journeys, 1854 ca. (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Development of Liaise Faire Capitalism/Social Darwinism in the United States, 1959-1975 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Distributive justice -- "Does Everyone Share the Burden?", 1973-1987 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Early America - articles about, 1963-1984 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Early America - articles about, 1963-1984 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Economic/land reform, 1897-1986 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Education in the U.S., 1969-1971 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Edward Bellamy and the concept of utopia, 1965-1977 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Edward Bellamy on the regimentation of labor (extract from Looking Backward), and article on the magazine revolution of the 1890's, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Emergence of the Great Popular Author (EGPA), 1984-1986 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Emergence of The Great Popular Author (EGPA) - fame and income, 1897-1986 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Emergence of The Great Popular Author (EGPA) - fame and income, 1897-1986 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Emergence of The Great Popular Author (EGPA) - Alexander Dumas, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Emergence of The Great Popular Author (EPGA) - anonymity and use of pseudonyms by 19th century authors, 1822-1986 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - EGPA - Charles Dickens, 1872-1986 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - EGPA - Charles Dickens, 1937-1986 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - EGPA - general, 1867-1987 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - EGPA - general, 1867-1987 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - EGPA - Mark Twain, 1943-1984 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Emergence of The Great Popular Author (EGPA) - Mark Twain, 1943-1984 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - EGPA - Opera, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - EGPA - Poetry, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - EGPA - publishing, 1937-1986 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - EGPA - publishing, 1937-1986 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - EGPA - research plans, 1984-1986 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - EGPA - Secondary American and European Authors, 1850-1986 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - EGPA - Sir Walter Scott, 1853-1980 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - EGPA - Sir Walter Scott, 1855-1962 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - EGPA - Sir Walter Scott, 1932-1986 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Emergence of The Great Popular Author (EGPA) - Thackeray, 1951-1972 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - EGPA -Theatre, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - EGPA - Victor Hugo, 1915-1987 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - EGPA - Victor Hugo, 1915-1987 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - EGPA - Women, 1968-1984 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Ernest Hemingway, 1950-1954 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Europe and America - notes, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - European Image of America, 1952-1960 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - European Imperialism, 1961 ca. (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Evolution of the Imperial Presidency, 1977-1984 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Evolution of the Imperial Presidency, 1977-1984 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Excerpt from book The Great Anglo-American War of 1900 by Captain Anson, 1890 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Excerpts from Henry Adams' "The Tendency of History" and Cunliffe's notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Excerpts from Moncure D. Conway's "Republican Superstitions,", 1872 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - F. Scott Fitzgerald, 1951 ca. (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - F. Scott Fitzgerald, Mark Twain, H.L. Mencken, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - First person singular (3rd week), 1958 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - George Bancroft on Lexington and Cunliffe's notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - George Washington - general notes, 1958 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - George Washington - hero worship, 1969-1970 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - George Washington in pictures, undated (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - George Washington, Walt Whitman - notes, 1945-1987 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - George Washington, 1788-1792 (Presidential elections book), 1969 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Gertrude Stein, 1935-1950 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Graphic images of Abraham Lincoln and George Washington (see also Box 97), undated (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Guns and gun control - clippings, 1911-1989 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Guns and gun control - clippings, 1911-1989 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Guns and gun control - clippings, 1911-1989 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Guns and gun control - clippings, 1911-1989 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - "Harrigan and Hart" - articles from New Yorker magazine, 1955 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Henry Adams and the Adams Family, 1963-1965 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Henry James "The American,", 1948-1976 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Henry James "The American,", 1948-1976 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Heroism - Ancient and Mythological, 1961-1986 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Heroism - Emerson and Carlyle, 1961-1982 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Heroism - general, 1959-1984 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Heroism - general, 1959-1984 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Heroism - Joan of Arc, 1969-1984 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Heroism - Literary and Romantic, 1957-1981 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Heroism - older American models, 1908-1983 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Heroism - older American models, 1857-1970 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Heroism - older American models, 1922-1987 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Heroism - Outlaws and Bandits, 1958-1984 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Heroism - Saints and Martyrs, 1957-1978 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Heroism - The "Great Man,", 1917-1984 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Heroism - women, 1976-1981 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Heroism and Psychohistory, 1979-1985 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Heroism in America, 1970-1985 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - History of laws and courts in the U.S. - articles, 1977-1984 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - History of the hotel -- the Democratic Palace, 1872 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - How American is American Literature?, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Hubert Humphrey election memorabilia, 1968 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Idea of Property in American Literature and History - notes, 1962-1983 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - The Illustrated London News with article on regimental histories, 02/07/1953 (2 copies) (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Image and political psychology of Abraham Lincoln, 1984-1986 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Imaginary War novels, 1895-1982 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Imaginary War novels, 1895-1982 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Imaginary Wars - notes, 1982 ca. (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - "Indian Images of America" -- Center for International Studies, MIT, 1958 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Individualism in American -- introductory (1st week), 1956-1958 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - International Communication Agency, 1980 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Interpretations of American Identity, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Introduction to Contemporary History, 1959-1970 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Introduction to The British Army and the British People by T.H. McGuffie, 1954 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - The Invention of the Presidency, 1772-1987, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Is History a Science? - notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - J.L. Motley on the "Netherland Nation,", undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - John Dos Pasos, 1950-1952 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Kennedy assassination new clippings, 1964-1970 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Law, order, and disorder -- clippings, 1980-1983 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Law, order, and disorder -- reading lists, articles, notes, etc., 1968-1979 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Lecture notes for American literature, 1956 ca. (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Lecture notes on Abraham Lincoln, 1950 ca. (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Lecture notes on Benjamin Franklin, 1950 ca. (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Lecture notes on Brigham Young, 1948 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Lecture notes on Franklin Roosevelt, 1950 ca. (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Lecture notes on John D. Rockefeller, 1950 ca. (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Lecture notes on Thomas Jefferson, 1950 ca. (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Lewis, Sinclair, 1949-1955 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Library of America -- great American biographies, 1990 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Lincoln and Washington images, 1790, 1987 (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Literature and covert culture, 1960 (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Literature and Democracy in the U.S., 1790-1860 -- articles, notes, 1970-1975 (Box 59, Folder 19)
  - Lottery - District of Columbia newspaper articles, 1982 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Lottery -- manuscript "Lots for Everyone,", 1990 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Lottery -- notes and articles, 1960-1978 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Lottery -- notes and articles, 1968-1983 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Lottery -- notes and articles, 1973-1989 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Lottery -- other times and countries (not the U.S. and U.K.), 1978 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Lottery -- The Luck Principle, 1975-1981 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Lottery -- The Luck Principle, 1975-1981 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Lottery -- the United States, 1972-1977 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Lottery -- the United States, 1972-1977 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Lottery and gambling, 1908-1978 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Military ballads (originals), 1850-1860 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous articles and notes, 1838-1983 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous clippings and articles on George Washington, 1957-1958 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous materials, undated (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous notes on military, 1953 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous notes on Washington, DC and regionalism (includes photo), 1803-1984 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Mock warfare -- notes and research, 1894-1982 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Monarchy - general, 1976-1982 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Monarchy and Republic -- notes, 1849-1986 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Monarchy and the Americas - Synopsis, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Monarchy and the Americas, 1957-1986 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Monarchy and the Americas, 1957-1986 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Monarchy, Republicanism, and the Americas - convergence/interaction, 1900-1985 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Monarchy, Republicanism, and the Americas - convergence/interaction, 1900-1985 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Monarchy, Republicanism, and the Americas - convergence/interaction, 1900-1985 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Monarchy, Republicanism, and the Presidency, 1974-1986 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Monarchy, Republicanism, and the Presidency, 1977-1986 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - "Nation Takes Shapes, 1789-1837" -- afterthoughts, etc., 1819-1974 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - National Museum of American History - political Americana, undated (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Nationalism - notes, 1987-1990 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Nationalism/Separatism, 1986-1990 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Negro tactics of non-violence - news clippings, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Neo-conservatism, 1951-1959 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - News clippings - Bicentennial, 1976 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - News clippings - Presidency of Ronald Reagan, 1980-1987 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - News clippings - Presidency of Ronald Reagan, 1980-1987 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - News clippings - Presidency of Ronald Reagan, 1980-1987 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - News clippings of President Nixon and Watergate, 1974 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - News clippings on aspects of literature, 1950-1976 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Non-Transatlantic comparisons of cultures - notes, 1970 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Norman Grabo on Noah Webster, 1990 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Notecards - mostly on the subject of property, undated (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Notebook on political science, undated (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Notes -- topics for research in American Studies, undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Notes for contributions to journal Victorian Studies, 1853-1969 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Notes on "Access to Opportunity: Education, Horace Mann, 1796-1859", undated (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Notes on "Civic or Individual Enterprise,", undated (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Notes on "Conservative Affirmations,", undated (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Notes on "Jefferson, Madison, and Private Property,", undated (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Notes on "Political Access: Suffrage and Office Holding,", undated (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Notes on "The Modern Corporation: Lippman and Berle,", undated (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Notes on Alice James and invalidism, including student paper and exam, 1985 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Notes on American culture and character, 1952-1954 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Notes on American literature, 1950 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Notes on American literature, 1957-1960 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Anglo-American connections, 1952-1976 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Notes on Anglo-American publishing, undated (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Battle of Bull Run, 1956-1965 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Notes on bears, 1976 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Notes on chivalry and the military, 1960 ca. (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Notes on de Tocqueville, 1968-1972 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Notes on Henry James and Realism, 1985 ca. (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Henry James, 1985-1989 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Notes on Henry James, including student paper, 1985-1989 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Notes on Henry James, Jr., 1985 (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Notes on Henry James, Sr., 1985-1987 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Henry James' book Daisy Miller, 1985 ca. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Henry James' book The Bostonians, 1972-1979 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Henry James' book Turn of the Screw, 1986 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Jacksonian America, 1824-1964 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Notes on Jacksonian America, 1953-1964 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Notes on military tradition, undated (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Notes on political parties, 1854-1963 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Notes on private property in the United States, 1970-1983 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Notes on religion, undated (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Notes on slavery and property, North and South, 1980-1981 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Social Darwinism and Utopian novels, 1965 ca. (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Notes on U.S. Military Academy at West Point, 1960 ca. (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Notes on U.S. Presidents, 1956-1960 (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Notes on violence, 1966-1968 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Walt Whitman, including paper by Betsy Erkkila "Walt Whitman: A Revolutionary Formation,", 1984 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Notes on William James, including student paper, 1985 ca. (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Notion of comparative thinking, 1970 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Notions -- articles/general, undated (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Outline of literary history, 1987-1988 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Pageants - U.S. and Great Britain, 1916 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Panoramas as an expression of history, 1924-1983 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Paper cut-out book Paper Soldiers of the American Revolution, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Philanthropy - Andrew Carnegie and others, 1966-1970 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Photocopy of "Innocents from Abroad" (1878), undated (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Poetry and theater, 1950-1953 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Portion of thesis - "The Luso-Brazilian Economy, 1750-1780: Democracy and Self-efficiency", undated (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Portion of thesis on the gold rushes of California and Australia in the 1840s, undated (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Post modern novel and American language - notes, undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Presidency - 19th century views, 1886-1960 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Presidency - changing factors, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Presidency - folklore and symbolism, 1948-1966 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Presidency - general (including a photo of John Kennedy), 1970-1988 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Presidency - nationalism and reform proposals, 1966 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Presidency and Constitutional problems, 1966-1986 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Presidency as monarchy, 1977-1987 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Presidency of Richard Nixon, 1972-1973 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - President Nixon and Watergate, 1972-1976 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Presidential authority, 1925-1965 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Presidential election - transcript of third debate between Ford and Carter, 10/1976 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Private property - notes, 1975-1985 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Property - American colonies pre-1776, 1975-1977 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Property - Copyright guidelines from the Library of Congress, 1973-1982 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Property - Copyright, and patents, 1886-1989 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Property - Copyright, and patents, 1891-1987 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Property - correspondence with publishers, 1976-1982 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Property - early Nationalism, 1972-1976 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Property - Education, 1813-1981 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Property - European formulations, 1950-1978 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Property - European pre-1776 (Locke/Hume), 1960-1980 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Property - European pre-1776 (Locke/Hume), 1960-1980 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Property - European: Post, 1776 to 20th century, 1971-1982 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Property - excerpts from Maince J. Klain thesis on property rights, undated (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Property - impermanence, 1963-1984 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Property - Inheritance, 1972-1981 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Property - Jacksonian radicalism, 1950-1970 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Property - Literary attitudes in the 19th century (House of Seven Gables), 1964 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Property - miscellaneous notes, 1975-1978 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Property - Native Americans, 1973-1978 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Property - Native Americans, 1967-1984 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Property - Native Americans, 1964-1985 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Property - Revolutionary era, egalitarianism, commerce, 1961-1974 (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Property - Thomas Jefferson, 1973-1981 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Property - "The Dynamic Interpretation of Property,", 1956 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Property - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars colonial property dialogue, 1935-1982 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Property in American History and Literature, 1973-1974 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - The Propertarian Republican -- the U.S. uses of comparison, 1984-1985 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Psycho history, 1971-1984 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Reading lists on military history including Cunliffe's work, 1978-1984 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Reagan assassination attempt -- clippings, 1981 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Religion and the State, 1983 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Religion in America - Mormonism, 1920-1985 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Report on J.R. Zvesper's thesis "Modern Political Philosophy and the Origins of American Political Government, 1789-1801,", 1975 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Republican superstitions, 1834-1872 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Republicanism - notes, 1930-1982 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Republicanism qualified, 1964-1978 (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Republics outside the U.S., 1843-1986 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Republics outside the U.S., 1924-1983 (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - Research application and articles by Noel McLachlan, 1989-1990 (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - Reversals of contemporary views - journalistic, 1963-1980 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Reversals of contemporary views - literary, 1963-1980 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Reviews of Ordeal by Hunger (Donner party), 1962 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Rhetoric of Republicanism, 1822-1982 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Rhetoric of Republicanism, 1835-1977 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Richard N. King's "History and Freedom in the Thought of Isaiah Berlin" and Cunliffe's notes, undated (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Richard Nixon campaign publications, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Roger Kennedy and Smithsonian "Time Machine" project, 1981-1982 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Ronald Reagan -- cartoons and iconography, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Roosevelt family notes, 1959-1988 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Roosevelt family notes, 1969-1990 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Roosevelt family notes, 1977-1987 (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - The Royal Warwickshire Regiment, 1955-1956 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Sherwood Anderson and E.E. Cummings, 1952 ca. (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Similarities between the U.S. and England - notes, 1950-1967 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Similarities between the U.S. and England - notes, 1964 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Slavery - notes, 1973 ca. (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Slavery "black" and "white,", 1859-1977 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Slavery and the working man -- notes, 1910-1978 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Slavery in the United States, 1884-1978 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Social Radicalism - notes, undated (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Southern military tradition and West Point, 1965 ca. (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Southern uses of wage slavery argument, 1840-1970 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - St. John de Crevecoeur - revisited, undated (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - St. John de Crevecoeur - articles, 1968-1986 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - St. John de Crevecoeur - research notes, 1973-1974 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - St. John's College (Annapolis, MD) bicentennial, 1984 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Statue of Liberty - news clippings and postcards, 1981-1983 (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - "Stephen Crane and the American Background of 'Maggie'", 1953-1954 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Taxes and deficits - articles, 1976-1983 (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Theodore Dreiser, undated (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - Thomas Paine -- reputation, 1845-1978 (Box 73, Folder 1)